ABDULHAMID ADIO

FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Email | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio | +2348143783218 | Ibadan

SUMMARY

Full-stack web developer and open-source enthusiast with a love for clean code and accessible design, pair programming and remote work aficionado, background in developing efficient software applications in a global market. 2+ years of industry experience. Skilled mentor with the proven ability to manage a team of 7+ junior developers to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline and effectively track changes. Fluent in multiple languages, frameworks, and technologies. Strong skills include Database management and MySQL, Ruby, and JavaScript.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3, BootStrap5

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL, Postgresql

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

April 2022 - Present

MicroFlix - This is a TV series website displaying several movies, users can like and comment on a film. It is an open-source project I built along with another developer. View the repository on GitHub

- → Created the homepage layout by fetching data from a movie API.
- → Created the like button functionality which stores and fetches data from an API endpoint
- Built with: (JavaScript and Webpack)

<u>Covid Tracker</u> – This project is a web application for the coronavirus pandemic showing world statistics, and fetching the data from an API.

Built the entire front-end application with Javascript, React, and Redux. View the repository on GitHub

MICROVERSE

Code Reviewer (Part-time)

(Remote) November 2022 - Present

- Review junior developers and new student projects.
- Deliver assistance and support to over 20 students per week by providing feedback on coding via code reviews.
- Strengthen written and communication skills while working in a 100% remote environment.

Mentor (Volunteer)

May 2022 - December 2022

- Mentor 5+ junior web developers and provide technical support through code reviews.
- Propose improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provide advice and tips to 10+ developers on maintaining motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

April 2022 - October 2022

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Develop skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

UNIVERSITY OF IBADAN

May 2018 - May 2023 (In Progress)